Just because they serve you doesn't mean they like you.
Clerks is a comedy film directed by Kevin Smith.
Convenience and video store clerks Dante and Randal are
sharp-witted, potty-mouthed and bored out of their minds.
So in between needling customers, the counter jockeys play hockey on the
roof, visit a funeral home and deal with their love lives.
Dante, played by Brian O'Halloran.
Randal, played by Jeff Anderson.
Veronica, played by Marilyn Ghigliotti.
Caitlin, played by Lisa Spoonauer.
Jay, played by Jason Mewes.
Silent Bob, played by Kevin Smith.
Clerks is a 1994 American black-and-white comedy film
written and directed by Kevin Smith.
The film stars Brian O'Halloran, Jeff Anderson, Marilyn Ghigliotti, Jason Mewes, and Lisa Spoonauer, it presents a day in the
lives of store clerks Dante Hicks (O'Halloran) and Randal Graves (Anderson) as well as their acquaintances.
It is the first of Smith's View Askewniverse films, and introduces several recurring
characters, notably Jay and Silent Bob (played by Mewes and Smith respectively).
The film was initially shot for $27,575 before its film rights were purchased by
Miramax Films and $230,000 was spent on music licensing and editing.
It was shot in the convenience and video stores where Smith worked in real life.
Clerks had its premiere at the Sundance Film Festival on January 22,
1994, and was released in the United States on October 19.
The film received positive reviews and grossed $4.4
million, launching Smith's career.
Often regarded as a landmark in independent filmmaking, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film
Registry by the Library of Congress in 2019 as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
In 2006, a sequel was released, followed by a third installment in 2022.
The film explores themes of salesclerk, work, new jersey, gas station, loser.
The tone is lighthearted.